# **Daria Minina**

University of Amsterdam E-Mail: <a href="mailto:d.minina2@uva.nl">d.minina2@uva.nl</a>
Nationality: Dutch, Belarussian Homepage: <a href="mailto:https://dariaminina.com">https://dariaminina.com</a>

## **Summary**

I am a PhD Researcher at the University of Amsterdam under the supervision of Stefanie J. Huber and Cars Hommes. I received my MPhil in Economics with honors at Tinbergen Institute in 2020 and MSc in Economics with honors at the University of Amsterdam in 2018.

My primary research interests are Macroeconomics Expectations, Uncertainty, and Rational Inattention. I use survey data and laboratory experiments to study the expectation formation of economic agents.

#### **Positions and Affiliations**

 Visiting PhD Researcher, De Nederlandsche Bank (DNB), Economisch Beleid en Onderzoek

2020 - PhD Researcher, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam School of Economics, Center for Nonlinear Dynamics in Economics and Finance (CeNDEF)

#### **Research Interests**

Macroeconomic Expectations, Uncertainty, Rational Inattention, Monetary Policy Communication.

#### **Publications**

"Learning in a Complex World: Insights from OLG Experiments", Journal of Economic Behavior & Organization (2024), vol 220, pp. 813–837. with Cars Hommes, Stefanie Huber, and Isabelle Salle

### Working papers

## The pass-through from inflation perceptions to inflation expectations

(Deutsche Bundesbank Discussion Paper, 2023) jointly with Stefanie J. Huber and Tobias Schmidt

#### The effect of information on consumer inflation expectations

(DNB Working Paper #810, 2024) jointly with Gabriele Galati, Richhild Moessner and Maarten van Rooij

## Work in Progress

#### Learning about inflation from the housing market. Survey evidence

(status: got access to the data set; obtained empirical results) single authored

The effect of macro and micro shocks on firms' price-setting decisions. The expectations channel (status: got access to the data set; obtained first empirical results) single authored

### **Education in Economics**

2020 - University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

PhD in Economics

Advisors: Stefanie Huber, Cars Hommes

2018 – 2020 Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

MPhil. in Economics (with honors)

Thesis Title: "Equilibrium Selection through Laboratory Experiments in a complex

OLG economy"

Advisors: Stefanie Huber, Cars Hommes

2018 University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

Master of Sciences (MSc) in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Behavioral Economics and Game Theory

2015 Belarussian State University, Minsk

*Master of Sciences (MSc)* in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Mathematical methods in Economics

2009-2014 Belarussian State University, Minsk

Bachelor degree in Economics (with honors)

### Internships

September 2022- Deutsche Bundesbank, Frankfurt am Mein

November 2022 Advisor: Tobias Schmidt

#### **Academic References**

**Cars Hommes** Stefanie Huber **Tobias Schmidt** Professor Senior Researcher Associate Professor University of Amsterdam University of Bonn Deutsche Bundesbank Roetersstraat 11, Niebuhrstraße 5, Mainzer Landstrasse 46, 1001 NJ Amsterdam. 53113 Bonn. 60325 Frankfurt am Main. Germany

Netherlands Germany + 31205254246

C.H.Hommes@uva.nl shuber@uni-bonn.de tobias.schmidt@bundesbank.de

Maarten van Rooij Principal Economist De Nederlandse Bank

Spaklerweg 4,

1096 BA Amsterdam,

Netherlands

Maarten.van.Rooij@ecb.europa.eu

Gabriele Galati Senior Policy Advisor De Nederlandse Bank

Spaklerweg 4

1096 BA Amsterdam,

Netherlands

e.b.g.galati@dnb.nl

## **Teaching Experience in Economics**

University of Amsterdam

2023 - Teaching assistant for *Mathematics 1: Calculus* (Undergraduate Course,

Instructor: Jop Schouten)

2020 - Teaching assistant for *Multivariable Calculus* (Undergraduate Course, Instructor:

Maurice Koster)

Teaching assistant for Mathematical Economics II (Undergraduate Course,

Instructor: Jan Tuinstra)

Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

2020-2022 Teaching assistant for Behavioral Macro and Complexity Summer School

(Graduate level, Instructor: Cars Hommes)

Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

2020 Teaching assistant for *Econometrics II* 

(MPhil Course, Instructors: Bas van der Klaauw, Hans Bloemen)

2016-2017 Belarusian State University, Minsk

Teaching assistant for Corporate Finance

(Undergraduate Course)

## Awards, Scholarships, and Certificates

Scholarships Full scholarship, Tinbergen Institute scholarship program for Research Master

students

Amsterdam Merit Scholarship, University of Amsterdam

## **Conferences and Seminar Presentations**

2023	NBB Workshop on Macroeconomics and Survey Data (Brussels, Belgium); 3rd MORSE conference (Maastricht, the Netherlands); CeNDEF@25 workshop (Amsterdam, the Netherlands); SNB Research Conference 2023*; EEA-ESEM 2023 (Barcelona, Spain); 5th Behavioral Macroeconomics Workshop (Bamberg, Germany); Experimental Finance 2023 (Sofia, Bulgaria); IMEBESS 2023 (Lisbon, Portugal)
2022	The X International Conference in Economics and Finance (Vilnius, Lithuania); The 11th Nederlandse Economendag (NED) (the Hague, the Netherlands); Research Seminar at De Nederlandsche Bank (Amsterdam, the Netherlands); WE_ARE_IN Macroeconomics and Finance* (Basel, Switzerland); 4th Behavioral Macroeconomics Workshop (hybrid: online and in Bamberg, Germany); 12th annual meeting of the Society for Experimental Finance (Bonn, Germany); 12th Workshop on Theoretical and Experimental Macroeconomics (Berlin, Germany); 49th OeNB Economic Conference and 35th SUERF Colloquium (Vienna, Austria)
2021	Brown Bag Seminar of the Research Centre of Deutsche Bundesbank* (Frankfurt, Germany); 27th International Conference on Computing in Economics and Finance (online)
2019	2018 Conference of Young Researchers in Economics and Finance (Minsk, Belarus)

<sup>\* -</sup> presented by a co-author

## **Professional and Academic Experience**

10/2017 – 06/2018	Centre for Blended Learning, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam Student Assistant (designed educational modules for the online platform)
11/2016 – 08/2017	Embassy of the United Kingdom in Belarus, Minsk Economic Diplomacy Assistant
06/2015 – 10/2016	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Senior economist (full-time)
07/2014 – 16/2015	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Leading economist (full-time)
09/2013 – 07/2014	Research Institute of the Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Junior Research Fellow (Internship)
07/2007 – 04/2014	BPS-Sberbank, Minsk Economist
Camanutan Okilla	

**Computer Skills** 

Matlab, R, Stata, Python, Eviews, Otree, Z-tree

# Languages

Languages Russian (native), English (fluent), German (intermediate), Dutch (intermediate)

# Other Training and Courses

June 14 – 2021	Online Experimental Finance Virtual Summer School, University of Bonn
April 19 – 23 2021	Online PhD course on Subjective Beliefs in Macroeconomics and Household Finance
June 20- July 1 2016	Institute for capacity development, IMF, Washington DC Certificate of completion (Course "Using DSGE-models for policy analysis")
December 4-18 2015	Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna Certificate of completion (Course "Monetary Policy Analysis")
March 2-13 2015	Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna Certificate of completion (Course "Macroeconomic Forecasting")
2013-2014  Online courses October 2016	BEROC, Minsk Certificate of completion (Postgraduate School in Economics)
	International Monetary Fund Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies II")
December 2015	Verified certificate of completion ("Macroeconomic forecasting")
November 2014	Verified certificate of completion ("Debt Sustainability Analysis")
July 2014	Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies")